

Software Engineer



atvahid@hotmail.com linkedin.com/in/alexander-vahid

260 Seneca Hill Drive, Toronto, ON, M2J 4S6 (647) - 632 - 1367

Highly motivated and enthusiastic Software Engineer with an interest in full time work and internship opportunities related to software development. I am confident that the software development experience I have gained at work and school, coupled with my soft skills such as being a great team player and communicator, would help me to have a positive contribution towards overall growth of your company.

# **Work Experience**

#### **EMBROSS**

Platform Software Engineer

JUL 2021 - Present | Toronto, ON

- Developed software in middleware programming with various languages such as C/C++, C#, and Java over mainly Windows OS environment
- · Performed troubleshooting and debugging to resolve technical challenges for customers, across self-service platform and application
- · Installed and maintained Self-service Platform
- · Participated in daily scrum and project meetings, and was a key contributor
- · Communicated with clients' technical contacts or 3rd party vendors to discuss technical terms

## **OAKVILLE PUBLIC LIBRARY**

Innovation Accelerator Team Member (Part of Sheridan Program)

FEB 2021 - APR 2021 | Oakville, ON

- · Worked with a team of 2 others to design a strategy for how OPL can effectively make improvements to its services for library patrons amidst the pandemic
- · Connected with OPL to determine their needs and existing strategies in place
- Developed UI wireframes (using Figma) for a prototype room booking feature to be integrated into the current OPL mobile app
- · Delivered a pitch to OPL executives for the room booking feature, receiving positive feedback and a 90% grade

### THE HOME DEPOT

Sales Associate

MAR 2019 - MAY 2020 | Oakville, ON

- · Informed customers about various services as well as products and their details in store
- · Sold heavy-duty products to customers (BBQs, Sheds, Lawn Maintenance Equipment)
- · Handled online customer orders and curb side pickup

### Education

### **BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE | SHERIDAN COLLEGE**

2016 - 2021 | Oakville, ON

- Languages learned: C/C++, Python, Java, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, Swift
- **Related courses:** Data Structures & Algorithms (1), Wireless Security (2), Software Engineering (2), Artificial Intelligence (2), Scripting & Web Languages (2), OS Analysis & Design (1), Advanced Mobile App Development (3)

# **Major Technical Projects**

## **WORD SEARCH GAME | MOBILE APP**

NOV 2020 - JAN 2021 | Side Project

- · A word search game app for Android where the user must find all hidden words in a grid of letters to win
- · Developed with Java in Android Studio
- · Tools used in development include Android SDK, ISON, and Gradle
- · GitHub Link: https://github.com/AlexanderVhd/Word-Search-Game

# **JOBPILL** | MOBILE APP

FEB 2020 - DEC 2020 | Capstone Project

- · Mobile job search and recruiting app that allows users to search (provides ability to filter) and post jobs
- · Developed with Java in Android Studio
- Tools used in development include *Android SDK*, *Gradle*, *Firebase* cloud hosted data storage, and the Google Cloud Platform's machine learning *Vision API*
- · Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/akopti/JobPill">https://github.com/akopti/JobPill</a>

## ALEXANDERVHD.IO | WEBSITE

JUL 2020 – NOV 2020 | Side Project

- · A responsive portfolio website
- · Technologies and tools used in development include Bootstrap framework along with HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- · Website Link: <a href="https://alexandervhd.github.io/">https://alexandervhd.github.io/</a>

# TWEET COUNTER | CONSOLE APPLICATION

OCT 2019 - NOV 2019 | Side Project

- · An application that implements a custom map reduce algorithm on a large twitter data set
- · Counts the frequency of the most used words in a person's tweets
- · Developed with Python
- · GitHub Link: <a href="https://github.com/AlexanderVhd/DM-Map-Reduce-Program">https://github.com/AlexanderVhd/DM-Map-Reduce-Program</a>

## **Skills**

SOFT SKILLS	TECHNICAL SKILLS	
Team Oriented	Java	MVC Architecture
Communication	Python	SQL Scripting
Time Management	C/C++	Android/IOS Development
Detail Oriented	HTML/CSS	Bootstrap Framework
Reliable & Accountable	JavaScript/TypeScript	Jira
Problem Solver	React	Git